Hello, Preppies.
How's it going?
Welcome to the IELTS Speaking Intermediate Course from PREP.
Let's begin with this question.
Describe a favorite toy in your childhood.
Many of you will think of toys like this, this, or this.
But the problem is, how can you describe your favorite toy fluently and clearly in the IELTS speaking test?
Just to think of it, it is so hard, right?
As normally, you don't talk about this topic even in your mother tongue.
So for today's lesson, we'll focus on a technique that will help
you describe objects or concepts more easily in the IELTS Speaking Part 2, which is T-I-D-F.
Now, let's go.
So what is the T-I-D-F structure, and why is it suitable for questions that ask us to describe something?
Let's figure it out through a sample answer to the question, Describe a favorite toy in your childhood.
To be more specific, I'll divide the sample answer into four paragraphs corresponding to T-I-D-F.
Each letter is an abbreviation of a noun that represents the main content of that paragraph.
Let's read the sample answer in two minutes and identify what these four nouns are.
Ready?
Your time starts now.
Do you have the answers?
Now, let's go through each paragraph and explore the T-I-D -F structure.
The first paragraph provides us with time when the speaker received the toy.
So T stands for time.
The second paragraph mentions the initial impression of the speaker.
Upon seeing the toy for the first time, so I abbreviates to impression.
Next, the third paragraph describes the physical features of the doll, such
as its adorable and huggable appearance, fluffy brown fur and sweet embroidered
smile, playful and charming look, perfect size, and its functions like provided
sense of security and became a source of comfort, and offer a soft reassuring hug.
This paragraph serves to provide specific descriptions of the doll, so D abbreviates to description.
Lastly, the final sentence mentions the strong emotions the author has for
the doll, such as it holds a special place and is loved, so F abbreviates to feeling.
Do you now understand what T-I-D-F is now?
Now, I'll give a more detailed introduction to the T-I-D -F structure, so that you can make the most of it.
Firstly, with the T time part, we'll provide information about the time
of the event, the time we knew or owned the object being described.
So, we'll need to answer two questions.
When did you know the object?
When did you own the object?
Next, with the I impression part, we will provide information about our
first impression of the object, so we'll need to answer the question,
what was your first impression of the object?
For the main content, the D description part, we'll provide specific
information describing the object's features and functions, so we need to
answer the question, what are features and functions of the object?
Lastly, with the F feeling part, we need to express our feelings and emotions about the object.
We can conclude by answering the following two questions.
How do you feel about the object?
What do you like most about the object?
Do you notice that this structure has a brainstorming idea approach similar to a technique we have learned?
Yes, that is the storytelling technique.
The structure of this technique includes introduction, background information, main events, and feelings.
To be more specific, both the TIDF structure and the storytelling technique use similar guided WH questions.
For example, the time and background information both discuss the time and
how the event started, and how the object was known, and they
both end with the feeling, where the emotions are expressed about the event or object.
The only difference lies in the description compared to the main events.
Description focuses on describing features, while main events focus more on time, order of activities, or events.
Another difference is that the TIDF structure does not necessarily need to follow a time order as the storytelling technique.
You can freely interweave or rearrange the components in a way that seems suitable.
So, what are the benefits of using this structure?
With a clear structure like this, we can make the most of
one minute to prepare for Speaking Part 2 answers effectively.
That way, you can always have ideas and know how to organize the order of your answer.
Moreover, this structure provides an outline rather than requiring you to
memorize sample answers, so you can flexibly change the content or even
rearrange the order of the components to fit different topics according to your preferences.
In today's lesson, I'll guide you to closely follow the TIDF order when organizing ideas.
But once you understand this structure thoroughly, you can be flexible in
rearranging it as TDIF, DTIF, and so on, as long as you
ensure that the content fully answers the questions in the cue cards and maintains coherence and cohesion.
Isn't it fantastic?
What are we waiting for?
Let's practice brainstorming ideas for today's Part 2 question based on the TIDF structure.
Here's the question based on the structure TIDF.
We have the following guided questions.
Describe a thing that you recently purchased.
You should say what it was, what it looks like, where you bought it, and explain how you felt about it.
Your task is to brainstorm guided questions based on the structure TIDF within 30 seconds.
Let's use the questions on the cue cards to develop the content for the story.
Ready, set, go!
Have you finished?
Did you encounter any difficulties in coming up with the guided questions?
Now, I will show you some suggested answers.
Based on the cue cards, I have the following guided questions.
For time, based on the cue card, I will immediately talk about
the specific object I intend to describe, the time and place of where I bought it.
So, I'll answer the following three questions.
What was it?
When did you buy it?
Where did you buy it?
For impression, I'll also talk about my first impression of the object.
So, I'll answer the question, what was your first impression?
Moving on to description, I'll mention the features and functions of the item.
So, based on the questions on the cue card first, I'll answer
the question, what does it look like?
When answering this question, we can talk about the features according to OSICOM.
Shape, size, colour, material, origin, etc.
So, I'll answer the question, what are its functions or benefits?
Finally, for feeling, I'll express my emotions about the object and expand my answer by saying what I like about the item.
So, I'll answer two questions.
How did you feel about it?
What do you like most about it?
Now, based on the questions in this template, please think of a specific outline in 30 seconds.
Your time starts now.
Based on these questions, I'll suggest a specific outline for you to refer to.
So, we have enough vocabulary and techniques to develop ideas for answering speaking part two questions.
Well done, Preppies.
Congratulations on successfully handling the question.
Describe object.
Let's take a look at the template of TIDF.
To master these techniques, don't forget to practice regularly, Preppies.
Now, let's call it a day.
See you guys in the next video.
Bye-bye.